<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NTH’s Site</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NTH’s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taipei Metro Route Map Using Historical Names</title>
      <link>/post/taipeimetrohistoricalnames/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/taipeimetrohistoricalnames/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonologic Phenomena of Old Chinese in Hokkien</title>
      <link>/post/ocinhokkien/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ocinhokkien/</guid>
      <description>Hokkien as a part of Min languages has a long history. Many believe that it can be traced back to the Han dynasties (兩漢) as some of the phonologic features still remain in Hokkien’s colloquial readings (白讀). In Tsai’s thesis, she constructed the transition of two Hokkien strata from the Han’s and the Six dynasties’ (六朝) speeches according to their different phonologic conditions. Here is an organized chart of how the Hokkien finals correspond to Old Chinese (OC) Rhymes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Vocabularies of Taiwanese Hokkien</title>
      <link>/post/basicvocabularieshokkien/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/basicvocabularieshokkien/</guid>
      <description>Personal Pronouns    Hokkien English Translation Examples     我guá “I” 我合汝無合伊來往。You and I are not close to him.   阮guán/gún Exclusive “we”Also used as genetive “my/our” 阮臺灣儂。We Taiwanese.阮老爸。My/Our dad.   㑑lán Inclusive “we”Also used as genetive “our” 恁是作武官，阮是作文官，㑑平平是政府其官吏。You are military officers and we are civilian officials, but we are equally officialdom of the government.㑑戍裏也有。We have it in our home, too.   汝lí Singular “you” 汝各飯坩，我也各碗籃。You are to rice pot as I am to dish rack, meaning we’re roughly the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Taiwanese Romanization System</title>
      <link>/post/etrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/etrs/</guid>
      <description>Unlike the POJ (Pe̍h-ōe-jī, Church Romanization), Enhanced Taiwanese Romanization System is only used as phoenetic alphabets instead as a writing system. It does not used hyphen to connect syllables like TL (Tâi-lô, Taiwanese Romanization System) does but transcripts character by character. This system is modified from TL and POJ to suit both Hokkien and Hakka. Below is the charts of Enhanced Taiwanese Romanization System, or ETRS for short.
Consonants    ETRS IPA for Hokkien IPA for Hakka Note     b [ b ] [ b ] In Hakka, b is only used in Chioon (詔安) dialect.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>